Special episode this week. We've
preempted the weekly show and there's
only three people we preempt the show
for. President Trump, Jesus, and Jensen.
And I'll let you pick which order we do
that. But what an amazing run you've had
and and a great event. Uh Every industry
is here. Every tech company is here.
Every AI company is here. Incredible.
Incredible.
>> Extraordinary and one of the great
announcements of the past year has been
Grok. When you made the purchase of
Grok, did you realize how insufferable
Chamath would become?
I had a I had an inkling that that that
>> We're his friends. We have to deal with
him every week. I know it.
>> to deal with him for the six-week close.
I know it.
>> two weeks. Two weeks.
>> It's all coming back to me now. It's
it's making me rather uncomfortable. The
The thing is uh
many of our strategies are are presented
in in broad daylight at GTC years in
advance of when we do it. Two and a half
years ago, I introduced the operating
system of the AI factory and it's called
Dynamo. Dynamo, as you know, is a
piece of instrument, a machine that was
created by Siemens to turn essentially
water into electricity. And Dynamo uh
powered the factory of the last
industrial revolution. So I thought it
was the perfect name for the operating
system of the next industrial
revolution, the factory of that. And so
inside Dynamo, the fundamental
technology is disaggregated inference.
Jason, I I know you're you're you're
super technical.
>> Absolutely.
>> it.
>> I'll let you take this one. Go ahead and
define it for the audience. I don't want
to step on you.
>> Yeah, thank you. I I I knew you wanted
to jump in there for a second. But it's
it's disaggregated inference, which
means the the pipeline, the processing
pipeline of inference is extremely
complicated. In fact, it is the most
complicated computing problem today.
Incredible scale, lots of mathematics of
different shapes and sizes. And we came
came up with the idea that you would
change you would you would disaggregate
parts of the processing such that some
of it can run on some GPUs, rest of it
can run on different GPUs, and that led
to us realizing that maybe even
disaggregated computing could make
sense. That we could have different
heterogeneous nature of computing. That
same sensibility led us to Melon II.
Yep. You know, today Nvidia's computing
is spread across GPU, CPUs, switches,
scale-up switches, scale-out switches,
networking processors, and now we're
going to add Groq to that, and we're
going to put the right workload on the
right chips. You know, we just really
evolved from a GPU company to an AI
factory company. I mean, I think that
was probably the biggest takeaway that I
had. You're seeing this fundamental
disaggregation where we've gone from a
GPU, and now you have this complexion of
all these different options that will
eventually exist. The thing that you
guys said on stage or you said on stage
was I I would like the high-value
inference
people to take a listen to this, and 25%
of your data center space you said
should be allocated to this Groq LPU GPU
combo.
>> to about 25% of the Vera Rubins in the
in the data center. So, can you tell us
about how the industry looks at this
idea of now basically creating this
next-generation form of disaggregated
prefill, decode, disag, and how people
do you think will react to it? Yeah, and
take a step back and
at the time that we added this,
we went from large language model
processing
to agentic processing.
Now, when you're running an agent,
you're accessing working memory, you're
accessing long-term memory, you're using
tools, you're really beating up on
storage really hard. You have agents
working with other agents. Some of the
agents are very large models, some of
them are smaller models, some of them
are diffusion models, some of them are
auto auto regressive models. And so
there's all kinds of different types of
models inside this data center. We
created Vera Rubin to be able to run
this extraordinarily diverse workload.
My sense is
And so we added what used to be a one
rack company, we now add a four more
racks.
>> Right. So Nvidia's TAM, if you will,
increased from what it whatever it was
to probably something call it, you know,
33% 50% higher. Now, part of that 33% or
50%, a lot of it's going to be storage
processors, it's called Bluefield. Some
of it will be a lot of it I'm hoping
will be Groq processors, and some of it
will be CPUs, and they're all going to a
lot of it's going to be networking
processors. And so all of this is going
to be running basically
the computer
of the AI revolution called agents. The
operating system of of
modern modern industry. What about
embedded application? So, you know, my
daughter's teddy bear at home wants to
talk to her. What goes in there? Is it a
custom ASIC, or does there end up
becoming much more kind of a broader set
of TAM with developing tools that are
maybe different for different use cases
at the edge and in embedded
applications?
>> that there's three computers in the
problem. At the at the largest at the
largest scale when you take a step back.
There's one computer that's really about
training the AI model, developing,
creating the AI. Another computer for
evaluating it. Depending on the type of
problem you're having, like for example,
you look around, there's all kinds of
robots and cars and things like that.
You have to evaluate
these robots inside a virtual gym that
represents the physical world. So it has
to be software that obeys the laws of
physics.
And that's a second computer. We call
that Omniverse. The third computer is
the computer at the edge, the robotics
computer. That robotics computer, one of
them could be self-driving car, another
one's a robot, another one could be a
teddy bear. Little tiny one for a teddy
bear.
One of the most important ones is one
that we're working on that basically
turns the telecommunications base
stations
into part of the AI infrastructure. So,
now
all of the It's a $2 trillion industry.
All of that in time will be transformed
into an extension of the AI
infrastructure. And so, radios radios
will become a edge devices. Factories,
warehouses, you name it. And so, so
there are three these three basic
computers
all of them, you know, are going to be
necessary. Jensen, last uh
last year, I think you were ahead of the
the rest of the world in in in saying
inference isn't going to a thousand
>> Just last year. Yes. Is it going to
>> feelings.
>> Is it going to one million X? Is it
going to one billion X? Yeah. Right. And
I think people at the time thought it
was pretty hyperbolic because the world
was still focused on pre-scaling, on
training. Here we are. Now inference has
exploded. We're inference constrained.
Um you announced an inference factory
that I think is leading edge that's
going to be 10 X better in terms of
throughput to the next factory. But yet
if you if I listen to what the chatter
is out there, it's that your inference
factory is going to cost 40 or 50
billion. And the alternatives, the
custom ASICs, AMD, others are going to
cost 25 to 30 billion and you're going
to lose share. So, why don't you talk to
us? What have you seen? How do you think
about share? And does it make sense for
all these folks to pay something that's
a 2 X premium to what others are
marketing? The big takeaway
the big idea
is that
you should not equate
the price of the factory and the price
of the tokens, the cost of the tokens.
It is very likely that the $50 billion
factory, and in fact, I can prove it,
that the $50 billion factory will
generate for you the lowest cost tokens.
And the reason for that is because we
produce these tokens at extraordinary
efficiency.
10 times, you know, the difference
between 50 billion Now, it turns out 20
billion is just land power and shell,
right?
>> Right. And then on top of that, you have
storage anyways, networking anyways, you
got CPUs anyways, you got servers
anyways, you got cooling anyways. The
difference between that GPU being 1X
price or half X price
>> Right.
is not between 50 billion and 30
billion. Pick your favorite number, but
let's say between 50 billion and 40
billion. Yeah. That is not a large
percentage when the $50 billion data
data center is actually 10 times the
throughput. Right. When you That's the
reason why I said that even for most
chips
if you can't keep up with the state of
the technology and the pace that we're
running, even when the chips are free,
it's not cheap enough.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Can I Can I just ask a general strategy
question?
>> Yeah. I mean, you're running the most
valuable company in the world. This
thing is going to do 350 plus billion of
revenue next year, 200 billion of free
cash flow. It's compounding at these
crazy rates.
How do you decide what to do?
Like, how do you actually get the
information? I mean, it's famous now,
these sort of emails that are people are
meant to send you, but how do you really
decide to get an intuition of how to
shape the market, where to really double
down, where to maybe pull back, where to
actually go into a green field? How How
does that information get to you? How do
you decide these things?
>> In a final analysis, that's the job of
the CEO. Yeah.
>> And our job is to define the strategy,
define the vision, define the strategy.
We're informed, of course, by amazing
computer scientists, amazing
technologists, great people all over the
company, but we have to shape that
future. Well, part of it has to do with
is this something that's insanely hard
to do?
If it's not hard to do, we should back
away from it. And the reason for that is
if if it's easy to do, obviously, Um
lots of competitors.
>> of competitors. Is this something that
has never been done before that's
insanely hard to do and that somehow
taps into the special superpowers of our
company?
And so I have to find this confluence of
things to that meets the standard. And
in the end, we also know that a lot of
pain and suffering is going to go into
it. Yeah.
>> There are no great things that are
invented because it was just easy to do
and just like first try, here we are.
And so if it's super hard to do,
nobody's ever done it before, it's very
likely that you're going to have a lot
of pain and suffering. And so you better
enjoy it.
>> So can you can you just look at maybe
three or four of the more long-tail
things you announced
and just talk about the long-term
viability of whether it's the data
center space or whether it's what you're
trying to do with ADAS and autos or you
know, what you're trying to do on the
biology side. Just give us a sense of
like how you see some of these curves
inflecting upwards and some of these
longer tail businesses.
>> Excellent. Uh physical AI, large
category.
We believe, and as I just mentioned, we
have three computing systems, all the
software platforms on top of it.
Physical AI as a large category.
It's
technology industry's first opportunity
to address a $50 trillion industry that
has largely been, you know, void of
technology until now. And so we need to
invent all of the technology necessary
to do that. I felt that that was a
10-year journey. We started 10 years
ago. We're seeing it inflecting now. It
is a multi-billion dollar business for
us. It's close to $10 billion a year
now. And so it's a big business and it's
growing exponentially. And so that's
number one. I think in the case of
digital biology, I think we are
literally near the chat GPT moment of
digital biology. We're about to
understand how to represent genes,
proteins, cells. We already know how to
understand chemicals. And so, the
ability for us to represent and
understand the dynamics of the building
blocks of biology, that's a couple of
two, three, five years from now. In five
years time, I completely believe that
the healthcare industry where digital
biology is going to inflict. And so,
these are a couple of the really great
ones, and you could see they're all
around us. Agriculture. Agriculture.
Inflicting now. No question. Yeah.
>> Jensen, I
I want to take you from the data center
to the desktop. Uh the company was built
in large part on hobbyists, video
gamers, and and all those graphic cards
in the beginning. And you mentioned in
front of, I think, 10,000 people here,
just clawed
uh open claw, clawed code, and what a
revolution agents have become. And
specifically,
the hobbyists, who are really where a
lot of energy um we see, you know, a lot
of the innovation breaks, want desktops.
You announced one here. Uh I believe
it's the Dell 6800.
Uh this is a very powerful workstation
to run local models, 750 gigs of RAM.
Obviously, the the Mac uh Studio sold
out everywhere. In my company, we're
moving to open claw everything. Freeburg
just got clawed peeled. You got clawed
peeled, I understand, and you're
obsessed with these.
What is this
from the streets movement of creating
open source
agents and using open source on the
desktop mean to you? So great.
>> Where is that going? Yeah, so great.
First of all, let's take a step back.
Um in the last two years, we saw
basically three inflection points.
The first one was generative.
Chat GPT
brought AI to the common
everybody, to our awareness. But the
fact of the matter is the technology sat
in plain sight months before GPT.
It wasn't until ChatGPT put a user
interface around it, made it easy for us
to use, that generative AI took off.
Now, generative AI, as you know,
generates tokens for internal
consumption as well as external
consumption. Internal consumption is
thinking, which led to reasoning. 01 and
continue that wave of ChatGPT grounded
information, made AI not only answer
questions, but answer questions in a
more grounded way, useful.
We started seeing the revenues and the
the economic model of OpenAI start to
inflect.
Then the third one was only inside the
industry that we saw, Claude Code, the
first agentic system that was very
useful, really revolutionary stuff. But
but Claude Code was only available for
enterprises. Most people outside never
saw anything about Claude Code until
Open Claw. Open Claw basically put into
the pop popular consciousness
what an AI agent can do.
That's the reason why Open Claw is so
important from a cultural perspective.
Now, the second second reason why it's
so important is that Open Claw
is open, but it
formulates
it structures
a type of computing model that is
basically reinventing computer
altogether. It has a memory system. It
scratch is a short-term memory file
system. It has It has It has scales.
Did you say skills or scales? Skills.
Oh, skills.
>> have scales, theoretically, yeah. Yeah,
skills. So So, the first thing first
thing it it, you know, it has resources
and it manages resources. It's It does
scheduling. Yep. Right? And cron jobs,
it could it could spawn off agents, it
could you know, it could decompose a
task and and cause and solve problems as
does scheduling. It has IO subsystems.
It could, you know, input, has output,
it connect to WhatsApp. And also, it has
a API that allows it to run multiple
types of applications called skills.
Yeah. These four elements fundamentally
define a computer. Yeah.
And therefore, what do we have? We have
a personal
artificial intelligence
computer for the very first time. Open
source. It's open source. It runs
literally everywhere. And so, this is
now the This is the This is basically
the blueprint, the operating system of
modern computing. Yeah. And it's going
to run literally everywhere. Now, of
course, one of the things that we have
to help it do is whenever you have
agentic software, you have to make sure
that an agentic software has access to
sensitive information, it could execute
code, it could communicate externally.
We have to make sure that all of it has
to be governed, all of it has to be
secure, and that we have policies that
it that gives these agents two of the
three things, but not all three things
at the same time.
>> Right. And so, the governance part of
it, we contributed to Peter. Peter
Steinberger was here, and and so, we've
got a mound of great engineers working
with him to help secure and keep that
thing so that it could protect our
privacy, protect our security. Jensen,
that paradigm shift makes some of the AI
legislation that has passed around the
country to regulate AI, and a lot of the
proposed legislation effectively moot,
doesn't it? Can you just comment for a
second on how quickly the paradigm shift
kind of obviates a lot of the models for
regulatory oversight of AI, which is
becoming a very hot topic in politics
right now? Well, this is This is the
part that that you know, we just with
policy makers, we need to we need to
always get in front of them, and Brad,
you do a great job doing this. We have
to get in front of them and inform them
about the state of the technology, what
it is, what it is not. It is not
a biological being.
It is not
alien.
It is not conscious.
Um it is computer software.
Yeah, exactly.
>> and it is not something that
um we say things like we don't
understand it at all. It is not true we
don't understand it all. We understand a
lot of things about this technology. And
and so so I think one we have to make
sure that we continue to inform the
policy makers and not affect not allow
doomerism and extremism to affect how
policy makers think and understand about
this technology. However however we
still have to recognize this technology
is moving really fast and don't get
policy ahead of the technology too
quickly. And the risk that we we run as
a nation
our greatest source of national security
concern with respect to AI is that other
countries adopt this technology while we
are so angry at it or afraid of it or
somehow paranoid of it that our
industries, our society don't take
advantage of AI. And so I'm just mostly
worried about the diffusion of AI here
in the United States. Can you just
double click if you were in the seat in
the boardroom of Anthropic over that
whole scuttlebutt with the Department of
War? It sort of builds on this idea of
people didn't know what to think. It's
sort of added to this layer of either
resentment or fear or just general
mistrust that people have sometimes at
the software levels of AI.
What you would do you think you would
have told Dario and that team to do
maybe differently to try to change some
of this outcome and some of this
perception? The first thing that I I
would I would say about Anthropic is
first of all the technology is
incredible. We are a large consumer of
Anthropic technology. Really admire
their focus on security. Really admires
their focus on safety. Um the the the
the the culture by which they went about
it, the the technology excellence by
which they went about it, really
fantastic. Um I I would say that that
the the desire to warn people about the
capability of the technology is is also
uh really terrific. We just have to make
sure that we understand that the world
has a spectrum and that that warning is
good, scaring is less good. Right.
>> Um
and because this technology is too
important to us. Right. And and I think
that it is fine to
uh
predict the future, but we need to be a
little bit more circumspect. We need to
have a little bit more humility that in
fact we can't completely predict the
future. And the ability and to say
things that that are quite extreme,
quite catastrophic, that there's no
evidence of it happening um could be
more damaging than people think. And and
of course we are technology leaders.
I
There was there was a time when nobody
listened to us. Yeah.
>> Um but now because technology is so
important in the social fabric, such an
important industry, so important to
national security, our words do matter.
And I think we have to be much more
circumspect. We have to be more
moderate. We have to be more balanced.
We have to be more for more thoughtful.
Well, I you know, I would nominate you.
I think the industry's got to get
together.
17% popularity of AI in the United
States. I mean, we see what happened to
nuclear,
right? We basically shut down the entire
nuclear industry and now we have 100
fusion reactors being built in China and
zero in the United States. Um we hear
about moratoriums on data centers. So, I
think we have to be a lot more proactive
about that. But but I want to go back to
this agentic explosion that you're
seeing inside your company, the
efficiencies, the productivity gains
inside your company. There's a lot of
debate whether or not we're seeing ROI,
right? And you and I entering into into
this year, the big question was are the
revenues going to show up? Are the
revenues going to scale like
intelligence? And then we had this kind
of Oppenheimer moment of 5-6 billion
dollar month by Anthropic in February.
Um
do you think as you look ahead, you
announced a trillion dollar, you know,
visibility into a trillion dollars of
just Blackwell and Vera Rubin over the
course of the next couple of years. When
you see this happening at Anthropic and
Open AI, do you think we're on that
curve now where we're going to see
revenues scale in the way that
intelligence is scaling?
>> When you look around when you I'll
answer this a couple of different ways.
When you look around this audience, you
will see that Anthropic and Open AI is
represented here, but in fact, every but
99% of everything that is here is all AI
and it's not Anthropic and Open AI.
Right. Right. And the reason for that is
because AI is very diverse.
I would say that the second most popular
model as a category is open models.
Number one is yeah, open open source,
open weights, open source.
Open AI is number one, open source is
number two, very distant third is
Anthropic, and that tells you something
about the scale of all of the AI
companies that are here.
And so so it's important to recognize
recognize that. Um let me let me come
back and say couple things. One, when we
went from generative to reasoning, the
amount of computation we needed was
about a hundred times. When we went from
reasoning to agentic, the computation is
probably another hundred times.
Now we're looking at in just two years
computation went up by a factor
10,000 X.
Meanwhile
people pay for information, but people
mostly pay for work. Yes.
Talking to a chatbot and getting an
answer is super great. Right. Helping me
do some research, unbelievable. But
getting work done, I'll pay for Indeed.
And so that's where we are. Agentic
systems get work done. They're helping
our software engineers get work done.
And and so then you take that you got
10,000 x more compute
you get probably at this point 100 x
more consumption now. Yes. Yeah. And we
haven't even started scaling yet.
We are absolutely at a million x. Which
is I think a great place to talk about
the number of
you have 20, 30,000 at the company
something We have 43,000 employees. You
know, I would say 30
8,000 are engineers.
Conversation we've had on the pod a
number of times is oh my God, look at
the token usage in our companies. It is
growing massively. And some people are
asking, hey when I join a company how
many tokens do I get cuz I want to be an
effective employee. And you postulated I
believe during your two and a half hour
keynote
pretty long keynote well done
that
you were spending
>> well done it would be shorter. Yeah.
Yeah.
So so you guys so you guys know so you
guys know there is no practice and so
it's a grip and a rip. Yeah. Yeah. And
so so I just wanted to let you know I
was writing the speech while I was
giving the speech. Okay. So Never know.
But
does that mean if we do I apologize. Do
back of the envelope math 75,000 in
tokens for each engineer something like
that. So are you spending in Nvidia a
billion two billion dollars on tokens
for your engineering team right now?
>> We're trying to. Let me give you a
thought experiment. Let's say you have a
software engineer or AI researcher and
you pay them $500,000 a year. We do that
all the time.
Okay. This is happening all of the time.
That $500,000 engineer at the end of the
year
I'm going to ask him how many token how
much did you spend in tokens and that
person said $5,000 I will go ape
something else.
>> Yes.
If that if that $500,000 engineer did
not consume at least $250,000 worth of
tokens I am going to be deeply alarmed.
Okay? And this is no different than one
of our chip designers who says, "Guess
what? I'm just going to use paper and
pencil. I don't think I'm going to need
any CAD tools."
>> And this is a real paradigm shift in
thinking about these all-star employees.
It almost reminds me of of what we
learned in the NBA when LeBron James
started spending a million dollars a
year just on his health of his body like
in maintaining it. That's right.
>> Here he is at age 41 still playing. It
really is, "Hey, if these are incredible
knowledge workers, why wouldn't we give
them
superhuman abilities?" That's exactly
what
>> Where does that go if we if we
extrapolate out two or three years from
now, what is the efficiency of that
all-star at an Nvidia and what they're
able to accomplish?
>> They're going to look like Well, first
of all, things that the the um wow, this
is too hard.
That thought is gone. Uh this is going
to take a long time. That thought is
gone. Uh we're going to need a lot of
people. That thought is gone.
This is no different than in this in the
last industrial revolution, somebody
goes, "Boy, that building really looks
heavy." Nobody says that. Nobody wow,
that mountain looks too big. Nobody says
that. Everything that's too big, too
heavy, takes too long,
those thought those ideas are all gone.
>> to creativity. That's right.
>> What can you come up with?
>> Exactly. Which means Now, the question
is, how do you how do you work with
these agents? Well, it's just a new way
of doing computer programming. In the
future in the past we code, in the
future we're going to we're going to
write ideas, architectures,
specifications.
We're going to organize teams. We're
going to give them We're going to help
them define how to evaluate the
definition of good versus bad. What's
the What does it look like when
something is a great outcome? How to
iterate with you, how to brainstorm.
That's really what you're looking for.
And I'm I think that every engineer is
going to have hundred a hundred agents.
Back to the PR problem the industry has
right now, you have executives
like David Freiberg with Ohalo, who's
looking at literally taking through the
use of technology, your technology and
AI, the number of calories produced and
making high-quality cal- calories. What
is the factor you think you can bring
the cost down, Freiberg, and what impact
does this vision have for what you're
doing?
>> zero-shot genomic modeling, and it
works. Yeah.
>> then you have that moment and you're
like, "Holy sh-
Honestly, like and and that's after
people are replacing entire enterprise
software stacks in a night. I did
something in 90 minutes I was telling
the guys about, replaced the whole
software stack and like a whole bunch of
workload, 90 minutes on cloud, ran this
agentic system, built the whole thing,
deployed it, and we got we were like
>> night.
>> Sunday night, 10:00 p.m. I was done at
11:30, I went to bed.
>> As the CEO, you replaced Yeah. And
everyone on my management team had to do
a similar exercise. Over the weekend,
what we saw on Monday, I was like,
"It's over." But, the technical stuff,
the science stuff,
we did something in 30 minutes using
auto research, and I'd love your view on
auto research and what that tells us
about how far we still have to go in
terms of efficiency. But, using auto
research and a chunk of data,
something was published internally that
we said, "Oh my god." And that would
normally be a PhD thesis that would take
7 years. It would be one of the most
celebrated PhD theses we've ever seen in
this field, and it would be in the
journal Science, and it was done in 30
minutes on a desktop computer running on
auto research with all the data we just
ingested. We got it on Friday, and we're
like, "Hey, let's try it." Try it. Boot
it up. Went to GitHub, downloaded auto
research, and ran it.
And you see everyone's face just go like
and then the potential of what this is
unlocking for us is like the kind of
thing that would take 7 years, and it
happened in 30 minutes.
And we're experiencing it in genomics,
and we're like, "This is unbelievable."
So, I I think like the acceleration
is widening the aperture for everyone in
a way that like you didn't imagine a few
years ago. But just going back to the
auto research point, can you just
comment on what you think about the fact
that this thing got published with 600
lines of code in a weekend and the
capacity that it has to run locally and
achieve what it can achieve with all of
these diverse data sets and what that
tells us about the early stages we are
in terms of optimization on algorithms
and hardware. The fundamental reason why
open claw is so incredible, number one,
is it's com- it's confluence,
it's timing with the breakthroughs in
large language model.
Yeah. It's timing was perfect. It was
impeccable. Now, in a lot of ways, Peter
wouldn't have come up with it probably
if not for the fact that Claude and GPT
and chat GPT have reached a level that
is really very good. Right. It is also
a new capability that allows these
models to tool use.
The tools that we've created over time,
web browsers and Excel spreadsheets and,
you know, in the case of chip design,
Synopsys and Cadence and uh
Omniverse and Blender and Autodesk and
all of these tools are going to continue
to be used. There's some Some people say
that that the enterprise IT software
industry is going to get destroyed.
There's it's There's a Let me give you
the alternative view.
The enterprise software industry is
limited by butts and seats. It's about
to get 100 times more agents banging on
those tools. They're going to be agents
banging on SQL, they're going to be
agents banging on vector databases,
agents banging on Blender, agents
banging on Photoshop. And the reason for
that is because those tools
are first of all do a very good job.
Second,
those tools are the conduit between us.
In the final analysis, when the work is
done, it has to be represented back to
me in a way that I can control. Right.
And I know how to control those tools.
And so, I need everything to be put back
into Synopsys. I want everything to be
put back into Cadence, because that's
how I control it. That's how I ground
truth.
>> Let me ask you a question about open
source. So, we have these closed source
models, they're excellent. We have these
open weight models, many of the Chinese
models are incredible. Absolutely
incredible.
Two days ago, you may not have seen this
cuz you were busy on stage, but
there was a training run that happened
in this crypto project called BitTensor
subnet 3. They managed to train a 4
billion parameter llama model totally
distributed with a bunch of people
contributing
excess compute, but they were able to do
it statefully and manage a training run,
which I thought was like a pretty crazy
technical accomplishment.
>> Yeah. Because it's like random people,
and each person gets a little share. Our
our modern version of folding at home.
Exactly. So, what what do you think
about the end state of open source? Do
you see this decentralization of
architecture as well and
decentralization of compute to support
open weights and a totally open source
approach to making sure AI is broadly
available to everyone?
>> I believe we fundamentally need
models as a first-class product,
proprietary product, as well as models
as open source. These two things are not
A or B, it's A and B. There's no
question about it. And the reason for
that is because models is a technology,
not a product. Models a technology, not
a service. For the vast majority of
consumers, the horizontal layer, the
general intelligence, I would really,
really love not to go fine-tune my own.
>> Right. I would really love to keep using
ChatGPT. I love to use Claude. I love to
use Gemini. I love to use X. And they
all have their own personalities, as you
know, which just kind of depends on my
mood and depends on what problem I'm
trying to solve. You know, I might, you
know, do it on X or I might do it on on
ChatGPT. And so, that that segment of
the of the industry is thriving. It's
going to be great. However,
they're
all these industries,
their domain expertise, their
specialization has to be channeled, has
to be captured in a way that they can
control.
And that it can only come from open
models. The open model industry we're
contributing tremendously to. It is near
the frontier.
And quite frankly, even if it reaches
the frontier,
I think that products as a service,
world-class products as as a models as a
product is going to continue to thrive.
>> Every startup we're investing in now is
open source first and then going to the
proprietary model.
>> Yeah, and the beautiful thing is because
you have a great router, you connect the
two by on on first day, every single
day, you're going to have access to the
world's best model.
And and then it gives you time to cost
reduce and fine-tune and specialize. And
so you're going to have world-class
capabilities out to shoot every single
time. Let Jensen, can I ask Of course.
Nobody wants the US to win the global AI
race more than you. Right? But
a year ago, the Biden era diffusion rule
really was an anti-American
diffusion of AI around the world. So
here we are a year into the new
administration.
Give us a grade. Where is Where are we
in terms of global diffusion and the
rate at which we're spreading US AI
technology around the world? Are we an
A? Are we a B? Are we a C? What what's
working? What's not working?
Well, first of all,
President Trump wants American industry
to lead. He wants American technology
industry to lead. He wants American
technology industry to win. He wants us
to spread American technology around the
world. He wants United States to be the
wealthiest country in the world. He
wants all of that.
At the current moment, as we speak,
Nvidia gave up a 95% market share in the
second largest market in the world
and we're at 0%.
President Trump That's right. President
Trump wants us to get back in there
and
and uh the first thing is
uh
to get license license for the companies
that we're going to be able to sell to.
We've got many companies who have
requested for licenses. We've applied
for licenses for them and we've got
approved licenses from Sec- Secretary
uh Lutnick. Uh now uh we've we informed
the Chinese companies and many of them
have given us purchase orders. And so
we're going to we're going to we're in
the process of cranking up our supply
chain again to go ship.
I think at the highest level, Brad, um
I think one of the things that we should
acknowledge is this.
Our national security
is
diminished when we don't have access to
miniature motors, rare earth minerals.
It's diminished when we don't control
our telecommunications networks. It's
diminished when we can't provide for
sustainable energy for our country. It
is fundamentally diminished. Every
single one of these industries is an
example of what I don't want the AI
industry to be. Right. When we look
forward in time and we say, "What do we
want What is the What does it look like
when American technology industry,
American AI industry leads the world?"
We can all acknowledge that there is no
way that AI models is won universally.
It is We can all acknowledge that is an
outcome that makes no sense. However, we
can all
imagine
that the American tech stack from
chips to computing systems to the
platforms are used broadly by the world
where they build their own AI, they use
public AI, they use private AI,
whatever, and they can build their
applications in their society.
I would love that the American tech
stack is 90% of the world. Yes. I would
love that. The alternative, if it looks
like solar, rare earth,
magnets, motors, telecommunications, I
consider that a very bad outcome for
national security. Agreed. Yeah. Yeah.
How much are you monitoring the
situation
with the conflicts around the world
right now, and how much does it worry
you, Jensen? So, China and Taiwan, and
then helium availability coming out of
the Middle East, I understand, can be a
supply chain risk to semiconductor
manufacturing. How much do these
situations worry you? How much are you
spending on them?
Well, first of all, I think the in
Middle East, I have we have 6,000
families there.
Uh we have a lot of Iranians uh at
Nvidia, and their families are still in
Iran. And so, so we have we have a lot
of families there. The first thing is is
they're quite anxious, they're quite
concerned, quite scared. Um we're
thinking about them all the time. Uh
we're monitoring and keeping an eye on
them all the time. They have 100% of our
support. Uh I've been asked several
times, are we still considering uh being
in Israel? We are 100% in Israel.
We are 100% behind the families there.
We are 100% in the Middle East. I was
also asked, you know, given what's
happening in the Middle East, uh is that
an area where we believe that we can
expand artificial intelligence to? Um
I believe that there's a reason we went
to war, and I believe that at the end of
the war, Middle East will be more stable
than before. And so, if we were there if
we're considering it before, we should
absolutely be considering it after. And
so, I'm 100% in on that. With respect to
with with with with respect to to
Taiwan,
we have to do three things. One,
we have to make sure that we
re-industrialize the United States as
fast as we can. Yeah. And whether it's
the chip manufacturing plants, the the
computer manufacturing plants, or the AI
factories, doing on that? We're doing
excellent.
With by by gaining the strategic
support, by gaining the friendship of
the supply chain of Taiwan.
By gaining their friendship, by gaining
their support, we were able to
build Arizona and Texas, California at
incredible rates. They're
They are genuinely a strategic partner.
Uh we we
we really they deserve our support, they
deserve our friendship, they deserve our
generosity, and they're doing everything
they can to accelerate the manufacturing
process for us. And so so I think that's
number one. Number two, we ought to
diversify the manufacturing supply
chain, and whether it's South Korea,
whether it's it's Japan, it's Europe, we
ought to we ought to diversify the
supply chain, make it more resilient.
And number three, let's be let's let's
demonstrate restraint.
And while we're
reducing uh increasing our diversity and
resilience, let's not
press, push
um unnecessarily. So we need to be
patient. It's helium It's helium a
problem?
A lot of reports out there.
>> I I think helium could be a problem, but
it's also the case that the supply chain
probably has a lot of buffer in it.
Yeah. These kind of things tend to have
a lot of buffer.
Uh but but um
you know. Yeah. You've um
made massive progress in self-driving.
Made a big announcement. You've added
many more partners including BYD. There
was just a video of you driving around
in a Mercedes.
And uh huge announcement uh with Uber
that you're going to have a number of
cars on the road from many different
manufacturers. Your bet is I believe
that there's going to be an Android
type open-source platform that you're
going to play a major part in with
dozens of uh car providers. And then
maybe on the other side there could be
an iOS with Tesla or Waymo. What's your
strategy thinking there and how that
chessboard emerges because it feels like
you have a pretty deep stack and in some
ways you're competing and in other
places you're collaborative. Yeah.
Um
it's taking a step back, we believe that
everything that moves will be autonomous
completely or partly
someday. Number one. Number two, we
don't want to build self-driving cars
but we want to enable every car company
in the world to build self-driving cars.
And so we build all three computers, the
training computer, the simulation
computer, the evaluation evaluation
computer as well as the car computer. We
develop the world's safest driving
operating system. Uh we also created the
world's first reasoning autonomous
vehicle so that it could decompose
complicated scenarios into simpler
scenarios that it knows how to navigate
through just like us, reasoning systems.
And so that reasoning system called
Alpaca IO has enabled us to achieve
incredible results.
We
open this we
we vertical optimization, we
horizontally innovate and we let
everybody decide do you want to buy one
computer from us? In the case of Elon
and Tesla, they buy our training
computers. Um do they want to buy our
training computer and our simulation
computers or do you want to let us uh
work with us to do all three and even
put the car computer in your car. So we,
you know, I our attitude is we want to
solve the problem.
We're not the solution provider.
And we're delighted however you work
with us.
>> to build on this question because I
think it's like it's so fascinating. You
actually do create this platform, a
thousand flowers are blooming.
But it's also true that some of those
flowers want to now go back down in the
stack and try to compete with you a
little bit. Google has TPU, Amazon has
Inferentia and Trainium. You know,
everybody's sort of spinning up their
own version of I think I can out-Nvidia
Nvidia.
Even though they also tend to be huge
customers. How do you navigate that? And
what do you think happens over time and
where do those things play in the
complexion of this kind of video
>> Yeah, really great. You know, first of
all,
um
we're the only AI company We're an AI
company. We build foundation models.
We're at the frontier of many different
domains. We build every single every
single layer, every single stack.
Um
we're the only AI company in the world
that works with every AI company in the
world.
They never show me what they're
building, and I always show them exactly
what I'm building. Right. Yeah.
And so so the confidence comes from
this. One,
uh we are delighted to compete on what
is the best technology. And to the
extent that to the extent that we can
continue to run fast, I believe that
buying from Nvidia still is one of the
most economic things they could do. And
I see this incredible confidence there.
Number one, number two, we're the only
architecture that could be in every
cloud, and that gives us some
fundamental advantages. We're the only
architecture you could take from a cloud
and put into on prem, in the car, in any
region.
>> That's right, in space. And so there's a
whole whole part of our market, about
40% of our of our business, most people
don't realize this, 40% of our business,
unless you have the CUDA stack, unless
you can build an entire AI factory, you
have the customers don't know what to do
with you. They're not trying to build
chips,
they're not trying to buy chips, they're
trying to build AI infrastructure. And
so they want you to come in with a full
stack, and we've got the whole stack.
And so surprisingly, Nvidia's gaining
market share.
If you look at where we are today, we're
gaining share.
>> what happens is these guys try and they
realize, "Oh my god,
it's too much." And then they come back.
Is that why their share grows?
Well, we're gaining share for several
reasons. One,
um our velocity has gone
we help people realize it's not about
building the chip, it's about building
the system.
And that system's really hard to build.
Uh and and so their their their business
with us is increasing. In the case of
AWS, I think they just announced, I
think it was yesterday, that they're
going to buy a a million chips
uh in the next couple years. I mean,
that's a lot of chips from from AWS, and
that's on top of all the chips they've
already bought. And so we're delighted
to do that. But number one, we're
gaining share this last couple years
because we now have Anthropic coming to
Nvidia.
Meta SL is coming to Nvidia.
And the growth of open models is
incredible, and that's all on Nvidia.
And so we're growing in share because of
the number of models. We're also growing
in share because outs
all of these companies are outside the
cloud, and they're growing regionally,
in enterprise, in industries, at the
edge, and that entire segment of growth
is, you know, really hard to do if it's
just building an ASIC. Brad, related to
that, um and not to get in the weeds on
the numbers, but analysts don't seem to
believe, right? So if you look at the
consensus forecast, you said compute
could 1 million X, right? And yet they
have you growing next year at 30%, the
year after that at 20%, and in 2029,
which is supposed to be a monster year,
at 7%. Right? So if you just if you take
your TAM and you apply their growth
numbers, it suggests that your share
will plummet. Do you see anything in
your future order book that would make
that correct? Yeah, first of all, they
they just don't understand the scale and
the breadth of AI.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yeah, I think that's true.
Most people think that AI is in the top
five hyperscalers. Right. That's right.
There's also an orthodoxy around these
law of large numbers where,
you know, they have to go back to their
investment banking risk committee and
show some model.
They're not going to believe in their
minds that 5 trillion goes to 15
trillion. They're like it can go to it
can go to it can go to seven. Or they
need to have a 10 trillion-dollar
company.
>> It's all just CYA stuff that I think
they're
>> happened before, so you can't say it
will.
>> And and because because the you have to
redefine what it is that you do. There
was somebody who made an observation
recently that Nvidia
Jensen, how can you be larger than Intel
in servers?
And the reason for that is because the
CPU market of the entire data center was
about 25 billion dollars a year.
>> Right. We do 25 billion dollars a year,
as you guys know, in a very in the time
that we were sitting here.
And so obviously obviously
that was a joke. No, it's but it's All
in podcast and all that. Don't worry,
everything on the show is real. DON'T
WORRY ABOUT
WOW, OKAY. OKAY.
NO, THAT WAS NOT GUIDANCE. BUT ANYHOW,
ANYHOW, it the point is how big you can
be depends on what is it that you make.
>> Right. Nvidia is not making chips.
Number one, making chips does not help
you solve the AI infrastructure problem
anymore. It's too complicated. Number
three,
most people think that AI is narrowly in
the things that they talk about and hear
and see. Right.
>> It's AI is much Open AI is incredible.
They're going to be enormous. Anthropic
is incredible. They're going to be
enormous. But AI is going to be much
much bigger than that. Yeah. And we
address that segment.
>> about data centers in space for a
second. Yeah. Um
We're already in space.
>> How should the layman
think about what that business is versus
when you hear about these big data
center build-outs that's happening in in
on the ground?
Well, we should definitely work on the
ground first because we're already here.
And number one, number two, we should
prepare to be out in space. And
obviously there's a lot of energy in
space. Um the challenge of course is
that cooling
you can't take advantage of
conduction and convection. And so you
can only use radiation. And radiation
requires very large surfaces. And so now
that's not an impossible thing to solve
and there's a lot of a lot of space in
space. Um, but nonetheless
the expense is still quite there is is
there. We're going to go explore it.
We're already there. We're already
radiation hardened. We have we have
CUDA in satellites around the world.
They're doing imaging, image processing,
AI imaging. And and that kind of stuff
ought to be done in space instead of
sending all the data back here and do
imaging down here. We ought to just do
imaging out in space. And so there's a
lot of things that we ought to do in
space. In the meantime, we're going to
explore what is the architecture of data
centers look like in space. And it'll
take it'll take years. It's okay. I got
plenty of time.
I wanted to double click on health care.
I know you've got a big effort there.
We're all of a certain age where we're
thinking about lifespan, health span. I
mean, we all look great, I think.
Some better than others. I think some
better than others. I don't know what
your secret is, Jensen. I mean,
what what are you taking? What's off the
menu? You got to talk to me when we're
backstage. I want to know in the green
room what you got going on. Squats and
push-ups and sit-ups.
>> Perfect. Okay. Um,
but I work.
>> What you know in terms of the build-out
in health care,
where is that going? And what kind of
progress are we making? I was just using
Claude to do some analysis and saying
like where are all these billing codes?
We spend twice as much money in the US.
We get seem to get half as much. It
seemed like
uh, 15 to 25% of the dollars spent were
on these first GP visits. And I think we
all know like
Chat GPT and a large language model does
a better job more consistently today at
a first visit. So, what has to happen
there to kind of break through all that
regulation and have AI have a true
impact on the health care system.
There's several several areas that we're
involved in in
in health care. One
is uh AI
uh physics.
Uh and and that's or AI biology. Using
AI to understand, represent, predict
biology behavior, biological behavior.
And so that's one, that's very important
in drug discovery. There's second, which
is AI agents, and that's where the
assistance in helping diagnosis and
things like that. Open evidence is a
really good example. Hippocratics is
really good example. Love working with
those companies. Um I really think that
this is an area where agentic technology
is going to revolutionize how we
interact with doctors and how do we
interact for health care. The third part
that we're in involved in is physical
AI. The first one's AI physics, using AI
to predict physics. The second one is
physical AI. AI that understand the
properties of the laws of physics, and
that's used for a uh robotic surgery.
Huge amounts of activities there. Every
single instrument, whether it's
ultrasound or, you know, CT or whatever
instrument we interact with in a
hospital in the future will be agentic.
Yeah. You know, open claw in a safe
version will be inside every single
instrument. And so in a lot of ways,
that instrument's going to be
interacting with patients and nurses and
doctors in a very unique way.
>> so much investment in AI weapons. It
would be wonderful to see some
investment in AI EMTs and paramedics and
saving lives, not just taking them.
>> Yeah. Uh which I think is a great segue
into robotics. You've got dozens of
partners. We had this very weird
I I don't know what to call a lost
decade or 20 years of Boston Dynamics,
Google bought a bunch of companies, they
then wound up selling them and spinning
them out, where people just thought,
"Nah, robotics is just not ready for
prime time." And now here we have the
world's greatest entrepreneur at this
time, uh tied with you,
uh Elon Musk, doing Well, that was a
good save, I hope. Optimus,
uh pretty impressive. And then, other
companies in China
How how close is that to
actually
being in our lives where we might see a
chef, a robotic chef, a robotic nurse, a
robotic housekeeper, you know, these
humanoid factor actually working in the
real world, knowing what you know
with those partners and the fidelity,
especially in China where they seem to
be doing as good a job as we're doing
here or maybe better?
Um
we invented the industry largely.
America invented We could You could
argue we got into it too soon. Yeah. And
and we got exhausted. We got tired um
about 5 years before the enabling
technology appeared.
>> brain. Yeah, yeah. And we we just got
tired of it just a little too soon.
Okay, that's number one. But, it's here
now. Now, the question is how much
longer? From the point of
high-functioning existence proof,
high-functioning existence existence
proof to
reasonable products,
technology never takes more than a
couple two three cycles. And so,
a couple two three cycles would
basically be somewhere around 3 years to
5 years. That's it. 3 years to 5 years
we're going to have robots all over the
place. Uh I think I think um
uh China is is a formidable. And the
reason for that is because they're
microelectronics, their um motors, their
rare earth, their magnets, which is
foundational to robotics,
they are the world's best. And so, in a
lot of ways, our robotics industry
relies deeply on their ecosystem and
their supply chain. Um and uh and and
they're, you know, obviously moving very
quickly. Uh we're going to, you know,
our robotics industry will have to rely
a lot on it. The world's robotics
industry will have to rely on a lot of
on it. And so, so I think um
uh you're going I want some fast fast
movements here. Ultimately, one for one,
Elon seems to think we're going to have
one robot for every human, 7 billion for
7 billion, 8 billion for 8 billion.
>> Well, I'm hoping more. Yeah, I'm hoping
more. Yeah. Uh well, first of all,
there's a whole bunch of robots that are
going to be in factories working around
the clock. There's going to be a whole
bunch of factory robots that that don't
move. They move a little bit. Uh almost
everything will be robotic. What does
the world look like? Sorry, let me say I
think like this is one of the robotics
for me is one of the pieces that I think
unlocks
uh economic mobility opportunities for
every individual. Everyone now, like
when everyone got a car, they could now
go and do a lot of different jobs. When
everyone gets a robot, their robot robot
could do a lot of work for them. They
can stand up an Etsy store or a Shopify
store. They can create anything they
want with their robot. They could do
things that they independently cannot
do. I think the robot is going to end up
being the greatest unlock for prosperity
for more people on Earth than we've ever
seen with any technology before. Yeah,
no doubt. I mean, just the
the simple math at the moment is we're
millions of people short in labor today.
Right.
>> Yeah. Right. We're we're we're actually
really desperate in need of robotics.
And so that all of these companies could
grow more
if they had more labor. I mean, we're
we're number one.
Some of the things that you mentioned
are super fun. I mean, because of
robots, we'll have virtual presence.
Uh you know, I'll be able to go into the
robot of my house
and virtually operate it. I'm on a
business trip.
>> Right. Tell you what, walk around the
house. Walk the dog. Yeah, walk the Rake
the leaves. Yeah, exactly. Rake up the
dog. Maybe not quite that, but just, you
know, just, you know, wander around
Yeah. and just see what's going on in
the house, you know, chat with the dogs,
chat with the kids. Yeah. Yeah. That's
an Time travel is also we're going to be
able to travel at the speed of light,
you know, and so, you know, clearly want
to send our robots ahead of us. Yeah.
Not going to send myself. I'm going to
send a robot.
>> Right. You know. Check it out.
>> Yeah, yeah. And then I'm going to upload
my AI. Well, it's inevitable. It unlocks
the moon and it unlocks Mars as targets
for for colonization, which gives us
infinite resources. Getting back from
the moon is effectively zero energy cost
to move material back cuz you can use
solar and accelerate. So, you could have
factories that make everything the world
needs on the moon, and the robots are
going to be the unlock for enabling
that.
>> Distance no longer matters.
>> Distance doesn't matter. Yep.
>> Yeah. The more the more revenue we get
out of models and agents, the more we
can invest in building the
infrastructure, which then unlocks more
capabilities on models and agents. Dario
on Dwarkesh's podcast recently said by
2027-28 we'll have hundreds of billions
of dollars of revenue out of the model
companies and the agent companies, and
he forecasts a trillion dollars by 2030,
right? This is non-infrastructure AI
revenue. Um
I think he I think he's he's being very
conservative. I believe Dario and
Anthropic is going to do way better than
that. Wow. Way better than that. Wow.
So, 30 billion to a trillion. Yep. And
not And And the reason for that is the
one part that he hasn't considered is
that I believe every single enterprise
software company will also be a
reseller,
value-added reseller of Anthropic code,
Anthropic's tokens, value-added reseller
of OpenAI.
>> That's right. And they're going to that
that that part of their Look at this
logarithmic expansion.
>> Yes. Yeah. Their go-to-market is going
to expand tremendously this
>> think this year? What do you think in
that world is the moat? What's left
over? I mean, you have some moats that
are frankly, I think, as this scales
almost insurmountable. The best one that
nobody talks about is probably CUDA,
which is just like an incredible
strategic advantage.
But in the future,
if a model can be used to create
something incredible, then the next spin
of a model can be used to maybe disrupt
it. Sort of in your mind, what do you
think for these companies that are
building at that application layer?
What's their moat? Like, how do they
differentiate themselves?
>> Deep specialization.
Deep specialization. I believe that
um these models that they're they're
going to have general general models
that are connected into the
software company's agentic system.
Right. Many of those models are
cloud models and proprietary models, but
many of those models are specialized
sub-agents that they've trained on their
own Right. So, the call to arms for you
for entrepreneurs is, look, know your
vertical. That's right.
>> Know it as deep and as better than
everybody else.
>> That's right.
>> And then wait for these tools because
they're catching up to you and now you
can imbue it with your knowledge.
>> That's right. And the sooner you connect
your agent, the sooner you connect your
agent with customers,
that flywheel is going to cause your
agent to get It very very much is an
inversion of what we do today because
today we build a piece of software and
we say, what generalizes? And then let's
try to sell it as broadly as possible
and then sell the customization around
it. And we trap In fact, in fact, with
exactly right. We we create a
horizontal, but
notice there are all these GSIs and all
of these consultants who are specialists
who then take your horizontal platform
and specializes it into Exactly. And
that's arguably a five or six time
bigger industry is the customization.
>> It is. Absolutely.
>> Yeah, the whole That very much is.
That's right. So, I think that these
platform companies have an opportunity
to become that specialist, to become
that vertical. Right.
>> Yeah, domain expert.
>> I just want to give you your flowers. I
think it was three years ago you said
you're not going to lose your job to AI,
you're going to lose your job to
somebody using AI. And here we are, the
entire conversation has revolved around
this concept of agents making people
superhuman and the business opportunity
expanding and entrepreneurship
expanding. You actually saw it pretty
clearly. Have you changed your view?
>> Well, I I got this is the the doomer
doomer doomer doomer I'M NOT A DOOMER.
I DO HAVE NO,
you can hold space for I think two
ideas. One is there are going to be a
lot
>> That's spiral J Cal we call it.
There you can do it.
>> Well, that's just because he doesn't
hang out with me enough.
Well, we I mean we talk a little bit. Be
careful with We don't talk about
He will show up at your BREAKFAST TABLE.
HE'LL FOLLOW YOU AROUND. I'm not asking
for it. I'm just saying. He'll follow
you around. I'm not asking for it. You
can come with me and Tucker. We ski in
Japan every January. We love it. Me and
Tucker road trip.
Okay. There is going to be job
displacement and then the question
becomes
you know, do those people have the
fortitude, the resolve to then go
embrace these you know, technologies.
We're we're going to see 100% of driving
go away by humans. That's just
it's a that's a beautiful thing and the
lives saved but we have to recognize
that's 15 million people in the United
States, 10 to 15 million who are
employed in that way. And and so that is
going to happen, yes?
I I think I think that jobs will change.
For example, um there are many
chauffeurs today uh who drives the car.
I believe that though many of those
chauffeurs will actually be in the car
sitting behind the drive the steering
wheel while the car is driving by
itself. And the reason for that is
because remember what a chauffeur does.
In the end, these chauffeurs they're
helping you they're your assistants,
they're helping you with your luggage,
they're helping you I mean they're
helping you with a lot of things. And
and so
I would be surprised actually if the
chauffeurs of the future become your
mobility assistant and they are helping
you do a whole bunch of other stuff.
Yeah, and the car's driving by itself.
Right. The autopilot in planes created a
lot more pilots and didn't take any of
the pilots out of the cockpit. Even
though the autopilot is flying the plane
90% of the time. And by the way, while
that car is driving itself, that
chauffeur is going to be doing a bunch
of other work on his phone and he's
going to be making money doing other
things.
Doing other stuff, coordinating a a of
things for you, getting you know, yeah.
It's all the pie just grows in a way
that So so one of the things that that
that
Yes, every job will be will be
transformed. Um some jobs will be
eliminated. However, we also know that
many many jobs will be recre- will be
created. The one thing that I will say
to young people who are coming out of
school who are concer- who are anxious
about AI, be the expert of using AI.
Yes. How much Look, we all want our
employees to be expert at using AI, and
it's not not
not trivial. Not trivial. And so,
knowing how to specify, not to over
prescribe, leaving enough room for the
AI to innovate and create while we guide
it to the outcome we want, it All of
that requires a lot
>> You had this great advice to when you
were at Stanford, I think it was, which
is, "I wish to you pain and suffering."
Do you remember that? Yeah. Fantastic.
What's your advice to young people
around what they should be studying? So,
if they're sort of
about to leave high school.
Because now those are the kids that are
at this like really native They haven't
made a decision about college,
what to study, if at all go to college.
How do you guide those kids? What would
you tell them?
I I still believe that deep science,
deep math, um
language skills,
you know, as you know, language is the
programming language of AI now.
>> programming language. And so, as it
turns out, it could be that the English
major could be the most successful. And
and so, so I think I think um
I would just advise whatever whatever
education you get, just make sure that
you're deeply deeply expert in using
AIs. One of the things that I wanted to
say with respect to jobs, and I want
everybody to hear it, that in fact, at
the beginning of the deep learning
revolution, one of the
the finest computer scientists in the
world deeply deeply I deeply
deeply
respect but
that computer vision will completely
eliminate radiologists.
And and that the one at the one field he
advises everybody to not go into is
radiology. 10 years later
his prediction was at 100% right.
Computer vision has been integrated into
all of the radiology technologies and
radiology platforms in the world 100%.
The surprising outcome is the number of
radiologists actually went up and the
demand for radiologists is skyrocketing.
The reason for that is because
everybody's job
has a purpose
and it's task.
The task that you do is studying the
scans.
But your purpose is to diag- helping the
doctors helping the patient diagnose
disease. And so what's surprising is
because the scans are now being done so
quickly,
they could do more scans improving
health care.
But doing more scans more quickly allows
patients to
be
onboarded a lot more quick treated a lot
more quickly. And as it turns out
because hospitals enjoy making money,
too.
Right. They're doing more scans. They're
treating more customers and more
patients. The revenue's going up and
guess what? They need more And in a in a
in a country that grows faster,
productivity increases, a wealthier
country can put more teachers in the
classroom, not less teachers in the
classroom. You just give every one of
those teachers a personalized curriculum
for every student in the room. It makes
them all bionic and leads to a lot more.
Every single student will be assisted by
AI, but every single student will need
great teachers. Yeah. Amazing. Uh
Jensen, congratulations on all your
success and really this is an incredibly
positive uplifting discussion. We really
appreciate you taking the time for us.
He is the steward we need. You are I
think you need to be more
You need to be more People are about the
positive side of it. I think there's too
much doomerism is But I also think it
takes the humility to have this level of
success and be humble about we're making
software, guys.
Yeah.
And I think that that's actually really
healthy for people to hear. We have done
this before. We have invented categories
and industries before. We don't need to
go to this
scaremongering place. It does nothing.
And we get to choose, right? We have
autonomy and and agency. We get to pick
how to We sure do. deploy this. Okay,
everybody. We'll see you next time
on the All-In interview. Okay.
Well done, brother. Thanks, man. Good
job. Thank you, sir. That was awesome.
Good. Good.
>> You guys are awesome. Jason, thank you.
>> Look at this. Look at this big crowd
behind you guys.
>> Man, I think they're here for you.
I'm going all in.